Hello everyone, today we are going to make a Heyebian half-body skirt.
This skirt is a three-piece, we will learn how to fold the skirt version and create the Heyebian version.
In addition, we will learn how to improve the quality of clothing and how to use the right fabric for it.
First of all, please download the Ruffle Skirt Base file provided by the Marvelous Designer team in the Connect store.
Please go to the link in the top comment to download the file.
You can see that we have provided you with a top, pants and belt version of the file.
As the basis of the skirt, we want to create a half-body skirt, and then we will create multi-layered Heyebian details for it.
In the 2D window, select the circle tool.
At the same time, press Shift and Ctrl keys, then click and drag the mouse to create the center with the initial click position.
In this way, when we use the center of the belt as the initial point and drag the mouse, we can estimate the length of the skirt that was created at the end.
Delete the left side to make the skirt half-circle.
In the front position, we will create the waistline of the skirt version.
Use the plus point division tool to refer to the pink smart guide line to create the end point on the middle line.
Select the inner circle tool, click the end point, then drag the mouse to create the waistline.
Press Shift and Ctrl keys as before to click the center position to create the inner circle.
Use the free-form tool to merge the skirt version and the belt version together.
In the 3D window, place the skirt version in a position that is not interlaced with the virtual model and then start modeling.
Since the inner skirt is frozen, even if the skirt is interlaced with the skirt, the effect is relatively small.
Later, we will remove the excess part on the skirt version.
After selecting the middle skirt, drag and drag the selection box to search for the skirt version until the length is suitable.
To create the waistline skirt version, we select the half-circle skirt version and select the 3D arrangement position to be selected.
It is more convenient to sew and model the waistline directly on the flat skirt.
To make the waistline
เป 두 Top3
We Electrodot
Select the waistline and skirt line.
From the范图之后根据曲线生成内部线功能,选择根据曲线生成内部线功能,创建两个内部线对于内裡比较方便。
Create two internal lines
Next, let's create a cross-sectional strip
Use the internal line diameter table
Based on the internal line created, create additional internal lines
These internal lines will form a cross-sectional strip
The diameter value we set is the width of one side of the cross-sectional strip
I set 20mm
Now we are going to create another internal line on the other side
Maintain the same diameter value and select the reverse option
Use the outer cross-sectional strip
To create a new strip
The strip created by the cross-sectional strip
Will automatically arrange above the original strip in the 3D window
And will automatically create a line between the two strips
Use the dis-connect function
To remove the link between the two strips
Select the internal line to form the cross-sectional strip
And select the cut-off
Delete the excess strips
Only keep the cross-sectional strip
Freeze the cross-sectional strip
Adjust the cross-sectional strip
Increase the size of the cross-sectional strip
Open the simulation
If you think the cross-sectional fold is too much or too little
You can press Ctrl-Z
Return to the pre-monitoring state
Re-adjust the size of the cross-sectional strip
Re-monitor
If you want to adjust the width of the cross-sectional strip
You can select the outer strip of the cross-sectional strip
Then select the outer strip expansion in the menu on the right-hand side of the menu
You can adjust the width of the cross-sectional strip according to your needs
Click to confirm the application settings
The outer strip expansion can also be used to shrink the cross-sectional strip
Now let's learn how to shrink the cross-sectional strip
Reduce the width of the cross-sectional strip
Change the direction option from extension to shrink
Then set the cross-sectional strip
That is, reduce the width value
You can refer to the preview of the 2D window
After clicking to confirm
You will see that the cross-sectional strip becomes narrower
When the particle diameter is smaller
The cross-sectional strip will be more natural and more detailed
But considering the simulation speed
We will keep it at 20 for the time being
Delete the excess sewing line
What is the Где
Remove half of the 아빠
Create a line to sew on the waist
The time should be the span line
The
Thickness is 1
Select the half-group panels and select the symmetrical panel, panel and line in the menu in the right-click panel.
After creating the symmetrical panel, place the panel in the upper-right window.
Then create the line between the symmetrical panels and merge the left and right groups together.
You can delete the excess points if you need.
Then merge the horizontal panel panels together.
Open the simulation and wait for the half-group panels to be simulated.
After the simulation is completed, copy and paste all the half-group panels and arrange them in the 2D and 3D windows.
In the 3D window, you can rotate the panels appropriately to align the side lines.
Now we will open the simulation for the panel and line.
Thinly line the panel and the line from the 3D window.
To see what the panel is like, click OK.
Next, create a simulation of the seam line between the back panel and the belt panel.
Select the model model option in the menu.
Use the activate model model function .
Activate the arm of the virtual model
Set the particle diameter of the half group to 10
The particle diameter of the nuclear edge plate is 5
To get a better simulation effect
Now we apply the elasticity to the fold position
By applying the elasticity to the nuclear edge seam line
We can make a more realistic shrink effect for the seam line
After opening the simulation
If you want to modify the elasticity ratio
You can press Ctrl Z
Go back to the selection of these lines
Then enter the new value
We will apply a new fabric to the half group plate
And modify its physical properties to snow
And the
Z-axis
And now go to the next step
And we will make the front of the clay
And the snow
This is the final semi-permanent effect, and this is the end of this tutorial. Thank you for watching. See you in the next video.